techlector.com 2019-08-14

# Privacy Policy - TecHLecToR

In compliance with the EU GDPR, TecHLecToR (“us”, “we”, or “our”) operates the https://techlector.com website (the “Service”).

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information when you use our Service.

## What are cookies and why are they used in TecHLecToR.com

Cookies are small text files that a site, when visited, places on the user’s computer or on their mobile device through the browser. Using cookies will help the site recognize the user’s device on a future visit. We use the term cookie in this policy to refer to all files that collect information in this way.

It is important to note that the use of cookies does not collect personal data of the user, which remains anonymous for us.

You can configure your browser not to accept the use of cookies, in which case the customization of the experience will not be applicable, although it is still possible to access the content of our website normally.

On the [Wikipedia](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie) page, you can learn more about what cookies do and how they work.

We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.

We use your Personal Information for providing and improving the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, accessible at https://techlector.com

## What kind of cookie do we use?

Cookies, depending on your stay, can be divided into session or permanent cookies. The first one expires when the user closes the browser. The second type expires when the purpose for which they are served is satisfied (for example, for the user to remain connected) or when manually deleted.

In addition, depending on their purpose, cookies can be classified as:

  * ###  **Embedded content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

  * ###  **Performance Cookies**

This type of cookie remembers your preferences for tools found in the services, so you do not have to reconfigure the service each time you visit.

For example, in this type include:

  *     * Volume settings for VCRs or sound.
    * The video streaming speeds that are compatible with your browser.
  * ###  **Geolocation cookies**

Cookies are used to determine which country the site or service is used. This cookie is completely anonymous and is only used to help guide the content of your location.

  * ###  **Registration Cookies**

They are generated when the user is registered or later opened their session, and are used to identify you on the web and services with the following objectives:

  *     * Keep the user identified so that if you close a web browser, service or computer and at another time or another day re-enter the service or web, will remain identified, thus facilitating your navigation without having to identify. This feature can be deleted if the user presses the “Exit” feature, so this cookie is deleted and the next time that you enter the site the user will have to re-authenticate to be connected.
    * Verify that the user is authorized to access certain services, such as participating in a contest.
    * In addition, some services may use third-party connectors such as Facebook, Twitter, or Google. When you enter a service with network credentials or a third-party identification system, you authorize the third party to maintain a persistent cookie that remembers your identity and guarantees access to the service until it expires. You may delete this cookie and revoke access to the service through third-party social networks or third-party identification systems by updating your preferences on the specific social network.
  * ###  **Analysis Cookies**

Each time a user visits a site or service, a tool from an external provider (Google Analytics) generates a cookie on the user’s device. This cookie is only generated during the visit and will be used in future visits to anonymously identify visitors.

The main objectives are:

  *     *       * Allow anonymous identification of users browsing the website through the “Cookie” (identifies browsers and devices, not people) and therefore the approximate number of visitors and their trend over time.
      * Anonymously identify the most visited content and therefore more attractive to users.
      * If the user you are accessing is new or recurring.

  * ###  **Advertising Cookies**

This type of cookie allows you to expand the information of the ads displayed to each anonymous user of TecHLecToR.com.

Among others, if you store the duration and frequency of the views, the interaction with them, the patterns and/or behavior of the user, which helps to establish an advertising interest profile. Thus, you can offer advertisements related to the interests of the user.

Advertising management tools ( [AdServers](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ad_serving) ) from third parties are used for advertising [management](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ad_serving). These third parties can store cookies sent from TecHLecToR.com through users’ browsers and access the data stored in them.

Companies that generate these cookies have their own privacy policies.

TecHLecToR.com uses Google to manage these services. For more information, visit <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>.

  * ###  **Technical cookies**

Technical cookies are used on the Site for the sole purpose of making it possible to browse the site and allow you to use its features. These are always first-party cookies, as they are conveyed directly by us on the Site. Some technical cookies are essential to offer you an optimal browsing experience or to allow you to authenticate on the site, for example, to make a purchase on the Site or enter in your reserved area (so-called browsing cookies). Browsing cookies are normally session cookies and therefore, once the browser is closed, they are automatically deactivated. Other technical cookies are used to allow you to store some of your preferences (for example, the language or country of origin) without having to reset them during subsequent visits (cd functionality cookies). For this reason, functionality cookies are often persistent cookies, as they remain stored on your computer even after the browser is closed until the expiration date provided for them or until you have decided to delete them. As required by current legislation on privacy, for the installation of these cookies is not required your prior consent. Of course, you are free to block the installation of technical cookies, by changing the settings of your browser (read paragraph E, No. 1 to know how to do). Consider, however, that by blocking the installation of technical cookies, or subsequently eliminating them, the ability to access the site, to use all or part of it.

  * ###  **Other information**

As highlighted in the introduction to this statement, the Company collects and processes some of your personal data through cookies that it carries directly on the Site (first-party cookies). The Company acts as the data controller of this data, in compliance with the provisions of the Privacy Code. We will treat your data only with electronic tools, in a totally automated way and without human intermediation. Therefore, our employees and collaborators will never access the content of your personal data obtained through cookies. Some of our employees and collaborators, appointed by us as data processors, may carry out maintenance work on the computer systems that host your data, without ever being able to access their actual content. Personal data may be stored on servers managed by third parties (eg IT systems providers) or may be managed by subjects specialized in online advertising, acting as external data controllers on the basis of a specific appointment in writing by part of the Company. We inform you that, in compliance with the conditions and guarantees established by law, your data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area, which may not offer a level of protection of privacy and personal data protection comparable to that guaranteed by European privacy laws. Your personal data will not be disclosed to third-party data controllers nor will they be disseminated. IT system providers) or could be managed by subjects specialized in online advertising, acting as external data controllers on the basis of a specific written appointment by the Company. We inform you that, in compliance with the conditions and guarantees established by law, your data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area, which may not offer a level of protection of privacy and personal data protection comparable to that guaranteed by European privacy laws. Your personal data will not be disclosed to third-party data controllers nor will they be disseminated. IT system providers) or could be managed by subjects specialized in online advertising, acting as external data controllers on the basis of a specific written appointment by the Company. We inform you that, in compliance with the conditions and guarantees established by law, your data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area, which may not offer a level of protection of privacy and personal data protection comparable to that guaranteed by European privacy laws. Your personal data will not be disclosed to third-party data controllers nor will they be disseminated. who act as external data controllers on the basis of a specific written appointment by the Company. We inform you that, in compliance with the conditions and guarantees established by law, your data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area, which may not offer a level of protection of privacy and personal data protection comparable to that guaranteed by European privacy laws. Your personal data will not be disclosed to third-party data controllers nor will they be disseminated. who act as external data controllers on the basis of a specific written appointment by the Company. We inform you that, in compliance with the conditions and guarantees established by law, your data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area, which may not offer a level of protection of privacy and personal data protection comparable to that guaranteed by European privacy laws. Your personal data will not be disclosed to third-party data controllers nor will they be disseminated. your data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area, which may not offer a level of protection of privacy and personal data protection comparable to that guaranteed by European privacy laws. Your personal data will not be disclosed to third-party data controllers nor will they be disseminated. your data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area, which may not offer a level of protection of privacy and personal data protection comparable to that guaranteed by European privacy laws. Your personal data will not be disclosed to third-party data controllers nor will they be disseminated.

  * ###  **Comments**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

  * ###  **Media**

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

  * ###  **How long we retain your data**

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

  * ###  **What rights you have over your data**

If you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

  * ###  **Where we send your data**

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

##  **How to disable cookies on your browser**

Most browsers now allow the user to configure whether or not to accept cookies. These settings are usually found in your browser’s “options” or “Preferences” menu.

Here are the instructions for setting cookies in the main browsers:

  *  _Chrome_  : Settings -> Show advanced options -> Privacy -> Content settings. For more information, you can check Google support or browser Help.
  *  _Firefox_  : Tools -> Options -> Privacy -> History -> Custom Settings. For more information, see Mozilla support or browser Help.
  *  _Internet Explorer_  : Tools -> Internet Options -> Privacy -> Settings. For more information, see Microsoft support or the browser Help.
  *  _Safari_  : Preferences -> Security. For more information, see Apple Support or Browser Help.

Make your choices carefully. By blocking the receipt of all cookies indiscriminately, including technical cookies, without providing for a specific exception to the site, you may not be able to browse the Website or use all or part of its functionality. In addition, by deleting all cookies from the browser, technical cookies may also be removed and, therefore, you may remove the preferences you have set using the Site or not find the products or services included in your cart.

(2) Use our interactive tools or those provided by third parties To disable first-party profiling cookies, ie those installed directly by us, you can simply use the interactive button that appears in evidence in paragraph D of this statement. Your choice to oppose the use of these cookies will have no consequence on the ability to browse the site and use its features, and may be at any time revoked by using the same interactive button. To disable third-party cookies, consult the privacy information of third parties who install cookies analytics (see the previous paragraph C) or profiling cookies (see the previous paragraph D) to know the other tools at your disposal to manage, disable and delete cookies, and more generally to oppose their use. Remember that, disabling third-party cookies, (i) you oppose their use not only on the Site but on all Internet sites on which these cookies are used and (ii) the ability to browse the site and use its features will not be in no way affected. When you disable third-party cookies you will still see the banner in the home page on the site related to cookies; in this case, however, by closing the banner, scrolling the home page or clicking any item on the home page outside the banner, you will not receive any third-party cookies that you have correctly disabled. (i) you oppose their use not only on the Site but on all Internet sites on which these cookies are used and (ii) the ability to browse the Site and use its features will not be affected in any way. When you disable third-party cookies you will still see the banner in the home page on the site related to cookies; in this case, however, by closing the banner, scrolling the home page or clicking any item on the home page outside the banner, you will not receive any third-party cookies that you have correctly disabled. (i) you oppose their use not only on the Site but on all Internet sites on which these cookies are used and (ii) the ability to browse the Site and use its features will not be affected in any way. When you disable third-party cookies you will still see the banner in the home page on the site related to cookies; in this case, however, by closing the banner, scrolling the home page or clicking any item on the home page outside the banner, you will not receive any third-party cookies that you have correctly disabled.

(3) Use the [Your Online Choices website](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/), operated by the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance (EDAA) non-profit association, which provides information on behavioral advertising based on profiling cookies and allows Internet users to easily oppose (opt-out) to the installation of the main profiling cookies installed by advertising operators and used on Internet sites.

Before using this tool, we recommend that you carefully read the general terms and conditions of the Your Online Choices website, frequently asked questions ( [FAQ](https://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/faqs) ) and [user’s guide](https://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/opt-out-help).

Use Your Online Choices consciously. Although, in fact, Your Online Choices brings together many of the most important advertising companies that use cookies, some of the third parties that install cookies through the Site may not have joined Your Online Choices. Therefore, the use of Your Online Choices does not guarantee that you will receive third-party cookies by browsing the Site. Also remember that by deleting all cookies from your browser, even technical cookies issued by Your Online Choices to remember your choices could be deleted, making third-party cookies active again.

###  **Changes To This Privacy Policy**

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

 **Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please [contact us](https://techlector.com/contact-us/).

 _updated: 22/5/18_
